[music]
>> Good morning. You're watching the
program for Tuesday, March 3rd, 2026.
I'm Ted Rall. John Kiriakou is my
co-host. How are you, John?
>> Hey, Ted. Doing well, and you? Good.
Good. Um so, uh we're obviously we're
continuing to follow the uh US and
Israeli attack against Iran and how the
war is spreading throughout the Middle
East. Um once again, uh we have uh
replays of 2003 and uh differing
rationales for war. Yep. Uh
things are spreading throughout the
We're We're going to have our financial
expert uh Achilles Larrea joining us at
9:15. The stock market just opened half
an hour ago. And as predicted from the
futures market, the Dow Jones Industrial
Average plunged uh over 700, 800 points.
Um we're looking at a possible uh total
downward trajectory on the stock market
today of 1 to 2 percentage points.
That's a lot. Um and it's not good. Uh
defense stocks and oil companies being
the exception. Marco Rubio finally
explained the rationale for the war. He
said, and we'll get into that. And of
course, there's a series of primaries in
Texas uh where the futures of the
Democratic Party and and and Republican
Party are being sort of analyzed. Uh
we're going to read the tea leaves out
of that um and try to predict what's
going to happen there. Uh as always,
please like, follow, and share the show.
Uh we always love to get your questions
in the live chat on Rumble and on
YouTube. And uh for those of you who
piped in early with the aha um slides,
uh please bear in mind we currently have
like uh 49 questions in the queue. So,
we'll try to get to all of them, but
it's going to be a little challenging.
Um
and uh you know, we're over We're over
22,000 subscribers. So, thank you for
helping us our our show. Uh it's uh
really gratifying. Okay.
>> and this let me add real quickly. I I I
want to say thank you, too, for
subscribing to the show. This has been
completely utterly organic growth.
We've been guided very very wisely by
Robbie. True. Robbie understands these
algorithms way better than we do, but
really it's just because you guys get up
and watch every day that we're able to
continue doing it. Otherwise, we would
have walked away 6 months ago.
It's true. Thank you for that. And it
was Yeah, I mean it was definitely a a
slog um for months. You know, we're
basically like
>> It was tough. It's like is you know,
we're we're not making a penny. Like
does you know, is any does anyone care?
Does anyone want want us to do this? Is
this worth doing? Is this worth our
time? But I think that we've turned that
corner thanks to you guys. Um
Uh speaking of which, let's go and
quickly remind people because we need
Robbie. We do need you to help um pitch
in to help uh help us keep Robbie.
Please, we look for $1,000 every month.
It's the beginning of March. So, uh
please go to gofundme.com and go to
deprogramrobbie or go to
gofundme.com/effisinfrank/deprogramrobbie,
one word, and uh just do whatever you
can. Uh we will stop asking when we get
to $1,000. John and I each put in $500.
Um and I guess we should just get to it,
John. Um obviously, we'll get to Texas
later, but let's uh
>> And and we made a little mistake.
Achilles is is not going to be with us
today. It's tomorrow.
>> Oh, it's tomorrow. Okay. Uh all right.
Well, so uh we will
>> We've got a lot to talk about anyway.
>> Yeah, it's it's fine. And and we can
still talk about the economy even
without Achilles. Okay, so Real quickly,
I wanted to say that the Dow futures The
The market opens in 25 minutes. The Dow
futures are down almost 900 points,
1.8%. The S&P 500 is down 1.7%
the NASDAQ is down 2.2%
it's going to be
hideous today and now with the Strait of
Hormuz being being closed in the last
two days oil has gone from $66 a barrel
to $83
a barrel. Gas prices in the United
States literally went up an average of
10 cents yesterday. Yesterday in one
day. Yeah. Yeah. So yeah, so that's
we're just going to see more of that.
So okay. So we're going to
I I think we should just go John if you
don't mind can we just talk about Marco
Rubio? Yeah, let's talk yeah,
he needs a smack across the chops. So
Rubio you know basically
he he said look we you know under the as
we know under international law
you preemptive war is not allowed. You
have to either be directly attacked in
which case you can defend yourself.
That's legal or you could there can be
an imminent risk of attack like you know
the classic example is you look across
the border. I guess a good example would
be Ukraine and Russia be before February
of 2022.
You
Russian forces were massing and and
preparing to attack Ukraine. There was
Intel credible intelligence. If Ukraine
had attacked Russia first, they could
have made a credible case that they made
a
there was an imminent threat. There's
nothing like that here. All the experts
say that there were not going to be that
that Iran did not have nor was seeking a
nuclear
nuclear weapons program.
The long range missiles
there's no there's no indication that
Iran even began
researching or developing much less
manufacturing them. It would have taken
at least 10 years for them to get there
according to the intelligence
assessment. So Rubio goes on and says
well is Israel called us and said they
were going to attack Iran. So, they we
they said you got to be careful cuz then
the Iranians will retaliate against your
troops in the Middle East. Therefore,
you should you have to come to our side
and attack Iran also. Now, Jonathan and
I were both talking right before the
show. Um there is a doctrine under
international law, uh rule 20 of the
customary international humanitarian
law, specifically article 57 2 C of the
additional protocol passed in 1977. The
United States is a party to this and um
US soldiers and and and uh
and sailors are taught this in the
academies that they have to provide an
uh member state has to provide a a
warning when it knows that
there's going to be an unjustified
attack. So, Trump if Rubio's telling the
truth or then Rubio or Trump had a legal
obligation under US law and treaty law
to contact the Iranians and say,
"Listen, they're coming for you." And
It's called the duty to warn. maybe ask
the Iranians for a favor like since we
told you, do you mind leaving our our
guys alone? That would be great. Um and
you you know, also
what's to stop Trump from telling
Netanyahu, "If you do that, there will
be no more money and there will be no
more weapons from us."
George H. W. Bush was the last American
president to stand up to the Israelis.
It was on the issue of settler housing.
And he said, "If you don't stop with
these settlements, we're going to
suspend um loan guarantees." And the the
Israelis said, "Go ahead and try." And
he did.
And they suspended The Israelis
suspended um
uh
new housing for settlers.
It was temporary, but at least it
worked. And since then, we haven't had a
single president of either party willing
to stand up to the Israelis.
Do you believe Do you believe um
Rubio's story? I'm not sure I do. No.
I think that's just an effort to make
him look like or make us look like the
good guys.
Um I mean, the truth is there's no legal
justification here. And what's
interesting is uh you know, maybe
because of the fact that only one out of
four voters support this, uh all the
mainstream media outlets that normally
would be cheerleading a war like they
did in 2003,
they're all saying, you know, getting
experts to come on and say, "Yeah,
there's no justification. This is
illegal." And so on.
>> Right. Yeah, I think that's right.
It's uh
>> that's right. It's very, very different.
Um we could go in uh we Oh, and the
other thing is I guess the main news
today is that 787 Iranians so far at
least have died and six American
soldiers at least have died. And you
know what? If those If those numbers are
correct,
that is 20% of those deaths are
children. Mhm. From that uh school that
was bombed by the Israelis. Yeah, that's
just from that school. You know there's
more children there, too.
>> Um so uh yeah, so both interestingly um
we talked about this yesterday, John,
that uh Iran clearly is holding back
their more powerful weapons for later.
And uh they've decided to take a totally
different approach than they did
previously in their last two times that
they were attacked by this coalition. Um
but the But Trump also has said, "Oh,
we're about to hit them even harder."
John, what does that look like?
I think they're going to they're going
to start
Uh I think we're going to initiate more
sustained bombing um attacks. I think we
are going to probably send a third
carrier battle group.
Um I think that um
that we're going to begin diplomatic
work to bring other countries into it,
which would be just a terrible, terrible
mistake. Uh in fact, the the Greek in
the Greek press this morning, the prime
minister went out of his way
without being asked to say, "We are not
bombing Iran. We will not bomb Iran. We
don't have anything to do with the
bombing of Iran."
And I think he said that because he
knows that it's coming, but the request
to up the ante is coming. But meanwhile,
other countries, other US allies like uh
France and Germany are, you know, they
say that they're going to be
participating with defensive operations.
What what does that mean as opposed to
offensive operations? You know, Does
that have a meaning?
Is that a distinction without a
difference?
>> any of these countries have Patriot
missile batteries, they could send them
to the Emirates or Qatar or Bahrain,
Kuwait, Saudi Arabia.
Um
but even if they do have Patriot missile
missile batteries,
those are finite um arsenals.
And so, I think that's what that would
mean.
Um we
>> would That would I mean, we're talking
about a week or 2 weeks' worth of
defense. Kurt Swanson had this question
for me, but I don't see why you couldn't
answer it, John. Is it Are we the
closest we've ever been to needing the
25th Amendment re you know, getting rid
of with pulling out the president? By
the way, speaking of which, I just
posted J.D. Vance. J.D. Vance is the man
who would have to trigger it, the vice
president.
>> triggers it, and then gets a simple
majority vote from the cabinet in order
to remove the president. It's never been
done. No, no.
>> J.D. Vance said I I I want to get this
right. This is this morning, or sorry,
yesterday. Pres- This is a quote.
"President Trump will not get the United
States into a years-long conflict with
no clear objective. Iran can never be
allowed to obtain a nuclear weapon.
That's the goal of this operation, and
President Trump will see it to
completion."
I'm sorry, John. Um, didn't Trump
announce that Iran's nuclear weapons
program had been completely decimated
last time, a few months ago?
>> I think he used the word obliterated.
Okay, obliterated.
>> is a big word. Either he was lying to us
or these guys are lying to him.
Or he's lying now. That's right. And I
mean and so yeah, and there's not even a
statement like, well, we got pretty
close, but we really have to finish the
job. We were wrong. We meant 80%
obliterated. I mean
>> Right. Um, okay, so 25th Amendment, I
mean, I say yes. I think the president's
out of control and and should be
removed. I think
you know, he's he should have gone to
Congress. He didn't. Um, okay. So, let's
uh shall we do some questions? Yeah,
let's do questions. And and we we've got
to thank some people first. Oh, yeah.
Yeah, we've got to thank uh well, first
of all, Heartmade 99 lb 99. Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you. Really appreciate
that. Yeah.
Yeah, thank you.
And
>> thank you for five bucks from Tati Mary.
Good um, what do we think the off-ramps
for this war look like? It's a good
question. How likely is this this this
ends without becoming a long-term
conflict? I can I I can I answer the
second one? I think I think we're 50/50
on that one. I think that this I mean,
you know, the this this could I mean,
it's going to be weeks, maybe months,
but I mean, does it go years? I mean,
years is hard to fathom um, just given
the mismatch in weapons between the US
and Iran, but what do you think?
Yeah,
I
I think that if if the United States
really wants to destroy Iran,
it can destroy Iran.
Mhm. But
what does destruction look like? Mhm. I
My guess is it's going to be decades of
chaos. And like like we said yesterday,
Ted,
that's to Israel's benefit. It's not to
our benefit, nor is it to the benefit of
our friends and allies in the Gulf.
I You know, John, the more we talked
about this sort of very fleetingly when
we did the special shows over the
weekend, but I now I'm really convinced
that civil war is the most likely
outcome here. God almighty. And you know
what would be worse?
Um is and you know it's going to happen,
that the United States and the Israelis
are going to begin arming factions in
Iran. You said probably radical
factions. Most likely. Isn't that always
the case?
>> That's what we always Why is that, John?
Why do Why in Afghanistan did we arm the
Mujahideen as opposed to another force?
Why do we always go for the crazies like
the Taliban?
>> the white Russians versus the the red
Russians. Um
Yeah, I I don't know.
Yeah, I never understood what
>> always this very short-sighted analysis.
Always.
Like I mean going to help us win today.
Okay, these these really terrible
people, they're going to help us win
today. And if they win, then we'll deal
with them later. And or and they'll
they'll owe us. They'll remember us.
>> Oh, yeah, sure, cuz that always works
out so well.
>> [laughter]
>> That I think they always think that
though.
Um [snorts]
Okay, so let's see. Um and then off What
do the off-ramps look like, John?
Hard to Hard to see. Yeah, [snorts] I I
don't really see an off-ramp other than
just declaring victory and going home.
You wiped out most of the leadership.
Mhm. You know, and I think Trump was
hinting at it yesterday
when he said that uh
that the Iranians wanted to talk. In
fact, the reporting is that we want to
talk.
The reporting is that we approached the
Italians and asked the Italians to tell
the Iranians that we're interested in a
ceasefire, and it was the Iranians who
said no ceasefire.
Mhm.
Um by the way, I have some good news,
John. Um we uh Robbie 8 is is now
fulfilled. We have We have our $1,000.
So
So uh that's great. Thank you. We will
not be bugging you about that. By the
way, for someone who asked about this,
they saw that there was like a total of
$4,000 in there. That's because it's
been 4 months. So um
we go for $1,000 a month. So it's a
total I'm sorry about that confusion.
It's not a new GoFundMe every month.
It's an old GoFundMe. Maybe there's some
way that Robbie can like edit that in
order to explain that in the entry
because I could totally see why that
would be confusing. People like, "Hey,
you say you need $1,000, but there's
$4,000 in there." But that's spread out
over over time. For people who've been
watching the show, they know that to be
true.
Um okay.
Uh
John, this is a question from
Papadopoulos. Thanks for the 2 euros. Do
you think there will be Greek-Turkish
tension more than now?
I do.
I do. The Turks are probably
the most militarily powerful country
standing in opposition to Israel.
And the Greek government couldn't get
any more pro-Israel. You know, this is
funny the funny thing in Greece the the
Greek people are solidly anti-Israel
because they're pro-Palestinian.
But the Greek government is solidly
pro-Israel because Cyprus is sitting on
an ocean of natural gas
and the Greeks, the Cypriots, the
Israelis, to a lesser extent the
Egyptians, are lifting the gas together
and sharing the money from it,
>> [snorts]
>> which is driving the Turks crazy, but
it's made the situation where as bad as
things are between Greece and Turkey,
they're sort of on track to get worse.
And then this war in Iran
doesn't help anything at all.
Uh
question for both of us and thanks for
the $4.99. Um how do we feel about the
nine dead Pakistani protesters killed
outside the U.S. Embassy in Karachi? Um
my I saw the video of that. It looked to
me like it was Consulate.
>> embassy guards who were or consulate
consular guards who were
firing at the Pakistanis, right?
>> Yeah.
>> were the Pakistanis trying to enter the
compound and I would imagine I would
imagine that's why.
>> in Pakistan is a country where American
embassies and American consulates have
repeatedly been attacked and they've
been burned to the ground. Um diplomats
have been murdered there inside the
embassy. Uh
Pakistan is one of the most dangerous
countries in the world if you are an
American. For sure.
It's not unusual for people to fire
rockets at the embassy, to shoot you as
you're coming out of the embassy parking
lot, you know, to throw Molotov
cocktails or hand grenades. And so, you
can't
you can't risk it spinning out of
control. You've got to You've got to
shoot. If you feel your life is truly in
danger, you've got to shoot. I mean, in
Pakistan, if you look like me or John,
you're dead. There's a good chance that,
you know, like just being in a cab,
people will throw rocks at you or, you
know, whatever or worse.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
It's happened to me. Um Italic, uh
John, what do you think about Italy's
position? And thanks for the 2 euros.
Um
the the Italians are trying to the the
Italians are trying to stay neutral as
best they can. The Italians actually
told us
that they would deliver such a message.
And in fact, the reporting is that they
did deliver a message that the U.S. was
interested in a ceasefire. It was the
Iranians who rejected the ceasefire uh
because they haven't yet begun fighting
back, not really. Let me add one other
thing. Several different people asked me
about um Kathimerini, the Greek
newspaper Kathimerini's documentary on
17 November. Have I seen it? I've not
seen it, but I'm in it. Um I sat for an
interview last March um that lasted like
3 hours, but I haven't seen it. I look
forward to checking it out.
Um John, um the it's it's all over the
press today that um the Trump
administration has no plan whatsoever
for post-war, post- uh Khomeini um uh
leadership, right? For what Iran should
look like. Yeah. Um this keeps
happening, right? And the thing is, I
mean, obviously the most
the the classic example is we didn't
know, you know, who was going to replace
the Taliban, and we were flirting with
the the the exiled king, who was living
in Italy, and then we find we we dredged
up Hamid Karzai, who was not widely
popular, I think would be fair to say,
um even from the very beginning. Oh,
yeah, we were flirting with Ahmed
Chalabi. We didn't know what we're going
to do about Saddam, and we never did
figure it out, really. Um Iran ended up
filling that power vacuum. But this this
US um you know, regime change thing, it
goes back to like World War II, right?
Like um you know, the FDR didn't seem to
know what he wanted to do about France
after D-Day, and he didn't want de
Gaulle, and I mean, what is with the
United States um not understanding cuz
over and over and over um they're told,
policymakers are told, you have to have
a plan for the post-war. You have to
have a regime. You don't overthrow
someone and create a power vacuum unless
you have someone credible to replace
them. Venezuela, I mean, I guess it kind
of like worked out because we just
kidnapped the dude, and the government's
still there.
What is happening here? I'm sure the CIA
um advises presidents to, uh, you know,
"Hey, here's a list of people who could
run this country you're thinking of
overthrowing." Um,
don't they?
Yeah.
Hey, before I answer,
uh, the United States just announced
that it is closing its embassies in
Saudi Arabia and Kuwait.
This is dramatic.
>> is it true that the Qataris shot down an
Iranian fighter jet?
You know, I saw the report and I didn't
see any confirmation. Yeah, that's
that's exactly it. Yeah. Um, all through
the the first Gulf War,
we never closed any embassies. I mean,
the Iranian Well, obviously, we had to
close Kuwait because it was
it was attacked and invaded and our our
diplomats were held as hostages, human
shields in Iraq. But, to close two
American embassies means that the White
House and the State Department have
decided that this is going to get a
whole all hell of a lot worse than what
it is right now. John, what are the
obligations that the US, um, emba-
embassies and consulates have to US
nationals and affiliates in a war zone?
I mean, over and over we're seeing these
facilities close, but other countries,
like the UK, is sending chartered planes
to try to rescue their nationals.
Usually, the US does that. Usually. But,
we're we're so deep into a hot war so
quickly,
like there was months in the run-up to
the Gulf War. There's no time to do it.
There was an announcement made yesterday
by the State Department urging all
Americans in the Persian Gulf to get
out. But, there's no flights. There are
no flights. And so, today
>> are closed.
>> Today, the the UAE government
said that any person, any Westerner,
stuck in a hotel
and unable to evacuate will have all of
his hotel bills paid. So, just stay,
relax, protect yourself, and we'll
figure things out later.
Well, I guess that I guess there's worse
things than that. That's very generous.
That's That's That's the Emiratis.
That's how they are. They're very
generous. But it's like what's what's
the uh
But like I just saw the official X um
you know, notification from the State
Department telling Americans in Israel
that they should get the [__] out and
leave as soon as they can, but that
there's no flights and that they're not
going to provide them with any
assistance. And the advice was on your
own. Try to make your way to Jordan. I'm
like, wait. So, you want them to make
their way through the West Bank right
now. Right now.
That's what you're saying. Freaking
believable. Right? Cuz yeah, where are
they going to go? Rafa is closed, so you
can't go to Egypt. You can't go to to
Lebanon. You wouldn't want to anyway
because
the Israelis and Hezbollah are fighting
in the south. You can't go to Syria cuz
it's no man's land. Yeah.
>> But you can't get to Jordan cuz you have
to cross the rest the West Bank and the
Israelis won't let you.
It's a It's It's It's really like man,
US passport is not worth not worth what
you think. Um Balint TCC, thank you very
much uh for uh the uh Hungarian forints,
4,000. I don't have no idea how much
that's worth. I'd like to think it's a
king's ransom, but I suspect it's not.
Anyway, do you guys think that the news
of 50% of Iran's missile launching
capabilities have been taken out is
true? If not, what do you think the true
figure is? Iran's missile capabilities?
Uh-huh.
Yeah, that's I mean, that's what the
Pentagon is reporting. The Pentagon is
saying that we've destroyed all these
these missile launchers. I saw I saw a
report yesterday saying that 50% of
Iran's missile launchers have been
destroyed, but
the Iranians can still
take deliveries from Russia and China
through the north.
And if the Russians have any idea what's
good for them,
they're going to try to get back to us
for for Ukraine by continuing to send um
surface-to-air missiles and missile
launchers to the Iranians. I would. I
would, too, big time. Um
LOL, thanks for the five bucks. Saudi
analysts say that that Israel attacked
their Aramco oil refinery, not Iran. Is
this another Israeli false flag? What
other false flags should we expect?
Uh speaking of false flags, on the other
side of that, Iran was accused uh by
right-wingers of attacking that school
themselves. Yeah, so stupid.
>> That didn't happen. I had a friend tell
me today that he uh does not wish to
speak with me any longer because he
posted he's he's very, very religious,
and he posted this thing on Facebook
saying that there are millions of people
in the streets in uh Iran, and that
they're all secretly Christian, and now
a Christian Iran's going to turn into a
Christian nation. And I And I will
literally not one single word of this is
true.
>> [laughter]
>> And he says, "Oh, because you're the
expert." And I said, uh
"Yeah."
>> [laughter]
>> Ridiculous. Um Johanna, thanks for the
$4.99. I'm in the process of enlisting
as infantry in the army. What are the
chances that we ever use boots on the
ground in this in this war? 48 hours
ago, I would have said we're not going
to do that because it's going to go very
quickly. And today, I'm going to say
it's probably a 50/50 prospect because
even after the president said
repeatedly, we are not going to send
boots on the ground, um yesterday
morning, Pete Hegseth, the Secretary of
Defense, said, "Well, not so fast." And
then the president refused to reiterate
his earlier position that we won't send
boots on the ground.
I think there's a chance. I do, too. I
mean, I don't know if it's quite at 50%
but we're we're moving toward that
direction.
Magnus Coronas, thanks for the 50
Norwegian Krona.
Why did Iran bomb all the Gulf
countries? We did address this so it's
just quickly though.
How would the Gulf countries react to
this when the Gulf countries aren't the
biggest fans of Israel? The Gulf
countries, I mean, I was just there in
the Gulf and we talked about this. They
would have they would have very
nervously just sat the whole thing out,
right? This is between the Americans the
Americans, the Israelis, and the
Iranians. But
you know, when you're blowing up hotels
in Dubai or the airport the civilian
airport in Manama and in Kuwait and
you're bombing of all people the the
peace-loving Omanis who have been trying
to broker peace between the two sides,
okay, then you've made a lot of enemies
that you really didn't need to make.
Goresh thanks for the five bucks on
Rumble. Uh Trump starts a war and you're
on your own to get out. What a prick.
I agree. Um
Uh
I would like um
B Wen, I would like thanks for the 10
euros. I would love for you guys to
invite Professor Chiang. He has some
great takes on the situation in
geopolitics in general. Robbie, please
look into that.
And Robbie, do we have an ad by any
chance?
All right. We're ready for it. We'll
take another question in the interim. Um
Okay, so um all right, let's get to some
of these aha questions slides questions.
Will China provide Iran with
intelligence and continue to sell them
weapons? Absolutely, yes.
Um Bahrain is buzzing with revolution
talk. Is it likely that a full-scale
uprising will occur? What would be the
consequences?
>> That is a very important question. So,
historically Bahrain had been between
2/3 and 3/4 Shia Muslim. The royal
family is Sunni Muslim. When I was
there, I was there during what Okay,
guys, new situation. Yeah, I I was
living there during what was then called
the Intifada. It became now known as the
first Intifada. And um and it was
freaking hideous, let me tell you. So,
what the what the Bahraini royal family
did in the intervening 30 years, I was
living there 30 years ago, is they
imported Syrians,
gave them Syrians are mostly Sunni
Muslims, gave them Bahraini citizenship,
and then started naturalizing Indian and
Pakistani Muslims, Syri- uh Sunni
Muslims. So, now it's closer to 50/50.
But, even though it's closer to 50/50,
the Shia
the Sunnis still have money, the Shia
are still poor, so there is always a
threat of an uprising in Bahrain.
Uh [snorts] let's do that Let's do that
spot. You've probably noticed Rumble is
growing fast, and it's not slowing down.
They're building a real alternative to
Big Tech that puts creators first and
actually protects free speech. And now
there's Rumble Premium, an easy way to
upgrade your experience. With Premium,
you get ad-free viewing across the
platform, no pre-rolls, no
interruptions, just the content you came
for. Plus, Premium members unlock
exclusive content like bonus videos,
behind-the-scenes drops, and more from
your favorite creators like John and
myself. Right now, Rumble is offering
$10 off an annual subscription. Just go
to rumble.com/premium
and use the code promo code studio at
checkout. That's rumble.com/premium,
promo code studio. No ads, more freedom,
and content you actually care about.
That's the deal. Um
Robbie, just a remi- Please remind
people why
they should consider migrating from
YouTube over to Rumble.
Yes, a few different reasons. One, from
a purely monetary standpoint, Rumble
pays a hell of a lot better. YouTube
pays pays off of your ads. So, you click
on a YouTube video, if you let the ad
run, the creators get paid.
Rumble, because Deep Program is part of
the Rumble creator program, is paid off
of watch hours. So, think about the TV
or radio. The more that you watch, the
more that they get paid. So,
basically for every nickel that they
make on YouTube, they make about 95, 96
cents over on Rumble. So, the money's
definitely there.
Uh also, if you are a channel subscriber
on YouTube, YouTube takes a nice
generous 40% cut off of your
subscription fee.
Uh
with Rumble, you subscribe for $5 a
month,
and John and Ted keep every penny of it.
Rumble doesn't take a dime for
themselves. One of the listeners is is
asking, "Robbie, what about the the
reputation Rumble has for being
right-wing?" I mean, obviously,
We're changing that. John's not
right-wing. Yeah, exactly. Well, I mean,
So, let me Let's just suggest that for a
little bit.
When last year, when YouTube, the
progressive liberal platform,
demonetized John and Ted for almost 3
months,
Rumble didn't.
When the war with Ukraine started,
YouTube, not Rumble, deleted John's
channel. YouTube, not Rumble,
uh shut down and throttled Ted Rall's
channel. YouTube, not Rumble, removed
RT. So, if you're going to use YouTube
as your beacon of free speech, um
maybe you should consider moving to
Israel, because that's the kind of free
speech that you want. If you want free
speech, go to Rumble.
It's true. We've never once heard from
Rumble to say, "Please take this down,
take that down. We don't like the cut of
your jib." That we YouTube's been a lot
of trouble for us. And lastly, I mean,
the how y'all talked earlier No, at the
at the top of the show about the just
thanks for all the people coming and
watching,
when YouTube was paying a couple of
hundred dollars for uh for what John and
Tit are doing,
Rumble just off of people watching was
allowing them to pay their bills.
Not YouTube. Thank you very much,
Robbie. Just because it was just just
because someone's right-wing
doesn't mean that they're that they're
your enemy. That's true.
I can vouch for that. I got censored
more by the Nation and Mother Jones than
I ever did by Forbes or Fortune as a
cartoonist.
Slay 123 thanks for the 10 bucks. Didn't
you guys catch the president's war
briefing?
Beautiful. Oh my god, this is like
moving
beautiful curtains and the construction
in his new ballroom. At this point
idiocracy feels less like satire and
more of a documentary. What the [__]
You know, it's the gold leaf that I just
don't get.
>> [laughter]
>> There's gold leaf everywhere.
Everywhere. It's going to all have to be
taken down.
It's just a waste of time and money.
It's
you know, it's like the decor is early
Dolomite if you are.
>> [laughter]
>> Do we think Gulf countries want the US
to build bases that have been damaged? I
guess rebuilt, sorry.
From Breed, thanks for the 499.
That's a good question. I mean, the
damage hasn't been very extensive,
right? So Not not so far. Although
there's there's breaking news
Robbie highlighted for us that
Cutter is now bombing Iran if you can
imagine such a thing. A country of
250,000 people is bombing a country of
92 million people right now. The Cutteri
Navy has intercepted 15 minutes ago the
Cutteri Navy intercepted a ship full of
Iranian missiles and drones and is
>> [snorts]
>> is forcing it into harbor in Doha. John,
how good is the Cutteri military?
It's very tiny, but it's trained and
equipped by the United States.
So, it it's good.
It's good. The Qataris are The Qataris
are playing hardball right now.
Um it's been reported that Russia and
Saudi Arabia spoke on Monday. Any
significance to this?
Um yeah.
The The Saudis
You know, this is Mohammed bin Salman. I
mean, the guy is just the most
unpredictable
uh leader or deputy leader in Saudi
history.
They're You might as well keep the the
lines of communication open. Like, maybe
maybe the Russians can say something to
the Iranians while the Saudis say
something to the Americans and we can
all back off this thing.
Um by the way, I do want to John, are
you If you're okay with this, I'm
focusing on the on the questions related
to the war and and sort of prioritizing
those over other things, if that's okay.
>> Of course.
>> Um I've been seeing reports unconfirmed
that Israel has been bombing oil
infrastructure in Saudi Arabia and
blaming it on Iran. So, that's more um
Although, you know, you can see on
radar, you can see incoming missiles.
So, I
No, I I don't think the Israelis are
bombing Saudi oil fields. They don't
need to because the Iranians
For the last 40 years, the Iranians have
been targeting Saudi oil fields. Mhm.
Mhm. Uh now that the war has started, is
there any way to end it with peace in
the region and without an increase in
terror attacks?
Not the Not the second one.
>> [snorts]
>> Um what will the impact be if Congress
does take uh Trump's war powers away? I
don't think Doesn't look, John, like
that's going to happen, right? We're
going to see a vote, um but there's
enough
uh There's even though there's some
conservatives um who are um you know, I
think Thomas Massie, uh Rand Paul,
people like that who are going to vote
for the war powers resolution, but
there's also going to be the John
Fettermans and other Democrats in name
only who are going to cross the other
way, so it'll probably look kind of like
a normal vote in Congress that Democrats
try to get through that fails. Yeah, and
if it's written as a resolution, a sense
of the Congress resolution,
it's not going to have any any teeth or
authority anyway. If it's done as
as a, you know, bill being passed into
law, the president's going to veto it.
Um
let's see.
Over the past year, several current
Israeli former Israeli officials have
pointed at Turkey as the next strategic
threat to Israel. God, what a change.
They used to be buddies. Yeah, they used
to be close buddies, which is one of the
reasons why the
Greeks and the Palestinians were so
close.
Um
Yeah,
you and I should explore this more
deeply at some point, but
but let's say that let's say that the
Israelis are successful in Iran.
And and the Iranian leadership is
removed from from power, there's no need
to worry anymore about uh
about an Iranian nuclear program.
But the Israelis are always looking to
attack the next guy. Yeah, well, this is
that's the rest of this question from
our anonymous question here.
Uh does Turkey constitute a meaningful
military, diplomatic, or economic threat
to Israel? Not only in terms of
capabilities, I would say yes in terms
of capabilities, but also in terms of Oh
my god, just
uh just um it's just
it just it moved forward. I'm sorry.
Anyway, Oh, that's okay.
>> you get the idea. Yeah, um
diplomatically, yes. I I do believe
diplomatically the Israelis have their
hands full with the Turks, but that's
life. Maybe the Israelis should
try to to start getting along with
people.
Um militarily, economically, no.
No, the the the Turks aren't going to
invade Israel.
No. No. No. Yeah, I don't think they
Yeah.
Um have you seen that Israelis are going
to advance troops into southern Lebanon?
They already have.
>> They did.
>> Greater Israel coming true. Although
they do that all the time, so it's hard
to say whether this is
>> time. There's this like 20-mi
no-man's-land
along the border. Yeah. Yeah.
Um okay. Thank you uh
Sorry. Um
Do we think Hezbollah's intervention
was a smart move for them? I mean it
does feel a little bit like nothing to
lose.
>> They've nothing to lose. But remember
Remember martyrdom is something to be
aspired to. Right.
Um is there a big John big big fan of
the content you produce.
I want to ask is there a reason why the
UAE and Dubai is being
disproportionately targeted compared to
other Emirates in the country other Gulf
countries be by the count of missiles
intercepted. Other question is that
reports are showing UAE and Qatar
running out of THAAD Patriot missiles.
How do you think that will play out?
>> Yeah, so the reports from last night
were that the UAE would be out of THAAD
missiles in 7 days and the Qataris would
be out of them in 4 days and we can't
resupply them quickly enough. So this is
a problem. I think that the reason why
the UAE has been so disproportionately
targeted is that the UAE has been at the
forefront of the attacks against the
Houthis. Mhm.
>> And um you know, despite the fact that
Dubai is is home to thousands of
Iranians and Iranian businesses, I think
the Iranian government just wants to
bloody the Emiratis' noses as best they
can.
Um what do you make of Marco Rubio and
Mike Johnson's suggestions that we
attacked Well, we talked about this
because Israel was going to attack Iran.
Um what could possibly be the PR
strategy of such statements from such
pro-war and pro-Israel leaders.
It's really
it is baffling. It's bad PR. I mean, I'm
interested in in crisis management. I
mean, they knew they were going to do
this, right? For at least months. So,
why did they Why do they not know how to
spin this? John, why is the president
still not speaking to the American
people?
You know, when he announced the the
attack, the start of the attack, he did
it
at 2:00 in the morning Mhm.
on Truth Social.
He did not address the American people.
He did not stand at the podium
in the East Room of the White House and
and make an announcement that
essentially we're at war.
He did it on Truth Social. And you're
right, he's only been going between
Washington and Mar-a-Lago back and
forth. He has not begun crisscrossing
the country to explain why he decided to
send young American men and women
into battle and put their lives at risk.
He owes that
Well, I mean
>> to the American people.
>> is I mean, the only thing I can think
of, John, is that the reason that the we
haven't seen a prime-time Oval Office
address to the nation is he wants to do
this as kind of a side project. He
doesn't want it to become a defining
feature of his presidency,
>> Right. But But you can't It can't not
be. It's so embarrassing. This morning
on NPR, they were playing all of these
clips of of him promising, you know,
criticizing Obama for attacking Iran,
saying, "I'll never get in I'll never
get you into any wars. These wars are
stupid. Why do we spend money on blood
and treasure overseas?" Over and over
and over. Yeah. And then this. I mean,
the American people aren't that sharp,
but they're not that stupid, either.
No.
No. And you've got to talk to the
people. You've got to explain the
policy.
And there's no there's no effort here at
all. I mean, I don't maybe he just
doesn't think maybe they don't think
that they could they have a good story
to tell. You know, I saw
um I saw a a clip on
I don't remember if it was BBC yesterday
or wherever it was. Um
where uh
they were interviewing Republican
voters.
Do you support or oppose the attack
against um against Iran? So, it was like
a third of Republicans support it,
two-thirds oppose it. And the supporters
are well, why do you support it? Well,
these are very these are very bad
people. Iran's a bad country or Iran is
a bad country. You're right. Like there
are a lot of bad countries out there. A
lot. You're going to attack all of them?
Like what are you nuts? It's it's a good
question. I've I've always wondered
that. I used to in the run-up to the war
against Iraq, I like used to compile all
the lists of dictatorships that the US
supports or tolerates around the world.
It's a long list. Um Ted, uh the markets
are now open and they're all crashing
and oil is skyrocketing. Okay, let's
take a look at that. Um looking at the
Dow Jones Dow Jones Industrial Average
is down over a thousand points right now
that with the market having opened 14
minutes ago. We're down 2.13%.
Oh my god.
I would say this is a free fall. Um this
is a free fall.
>> They're going to have to they're going
to have to shut down uh trading. Yeah, I
think well, there's there's use there's
automatic triggers. Um so, that probably
will happen.
Uh if they shut down trading, that's
going to be a huge signal. I mean,
look, this is this is something that the
president can't ignore, right? Um you
know, he's getting calls right now from
Fortune 500 CEOs are flooding uh the
administration and saying, "You're
[__] up the economy." Um
you know, Donald Trump doesn't want to
[__] up the economy. That's the one
thing he can't afford to do. Um but
then, let me ask you, why in the world
would gold and silver be crashing?
Gold and silver should be going up. And
they should be going up, and gold's down
3 and 1/3 percent, down $178.90.
The only thing I can think of is that
we're seeing some uh profit taking
because there's been uh you know, people
who invest in precious metals
traditionally do so over a longer
period. It's not something that they
trade in and out of in a day. And so, I
think you might have like people who
bought like a few months ago and
thinking like, "I'm going to get this
right now like while the market is is
high and and we'll see what I would
watch that." Um
if it keeps go I would that's really
going to be strange if it keeps going
down later in the day, but it could
bounce back.
Uh
>> Yeah.
Yeah, interestingly, what's the Rus- So,
the uh
the Russell interestingly, the small cap
Russell 2000 index is very small
companies, uh and that's up. That's
crazy. It's up. Yeah, mhm.
Yeah, that's So, that's super
interesting.
>> Um yeah, we are
uh Okay, now sorry, now it's dropping.
Uh yeah, okay. Okay, yeah. All right,
now it's falling again. Okay, so we
shall see what happens here, but Okay,
if you're the president, you're sitting
there, you're watching the you know,
he's getting this news.
Um what's How's the administration going
to respond to
uh a stock market crash? Knowing Donald
Trump, he is going to he's going to put
on a tough face, and he's going to say,
"Stay the course. This is the right
thing to do.
We're going to fight until we win. We're
going to destroy the Iranians and their
nuclear program, and everybody's going
to make money, so just stay the course."
Uh what are our thoughts on reports that
MBS of Saudi Arabia encouraged Trump to
attack Iran? I mean, we know that's
true. Um, who benefits from spreading
such reports? Do they have a net
positive or negative effect effect for
MBS or Saudi Arabia? I got to think
negative. I would think negative, too.
It doesn't make sense to me because it
was MBS's idea to try to normalize and
improve relations between Saudi Arabia
and Iran.
So, why
why attack?
I just don't get it.
Um, I do want to take this question even
though it's not about Iran. Um,
Eastern Congo is experiencing one of the
worst humanitarian crises on the planet
right now, has been for decades. 80% of
women there say they've been raped.
There are US-backed agreements that
critics say are designed to legally
extract their resources without consent.
We hear nothing about it with one out of
four people on Earth being African
within 50 years. Powerful interests are
already playing the long game over the
continent while we look away. What's
your specific position on US policies
toward the Democratic Republic of the
Congo? Any mission in Africa in the
past? I guess that question's for you,
John.
Um,
one mission in Africa in the past, in
Kenya, that I I'm sorry to say I'm not
permitted to to talk about.
Um, I'm not even sure I'm allowed to say
I had been in Kenya, but there it is. It
was a long time ago.
Um, and then when I was at the Senate
Foreign Relations Committee, yeah, I did
work in um,
Djibouti, Ethiopia, and Somalia.
You know,
the odd the odd thing is US
DRC [snorts]
uh, relations
are actually quite good. Mhm. We buy as
much of their rare earth metals as they
could possibly dig out of the ground.
We make everything from, you know,
from chrome bumpers to cell phones to
guided missile systems with their rare
earth metals. And that's what the DRC
government is very weak in the eastern
part of the country. Very, very weak
versus Rwanda of all countries. Rwanda's
like this big, DRC's huge, and the
Rwanda the Rwandans just just batter
them about the face and head at will.
It's it's chaos over there in the east,
but this is one of those conflicts that
Donald Trump took credit for solving.
This was one of his arguments in support
of the Nobel Peace Prize that he brought
peace to the eastern
Congo. And the peace lasted a couple of
weeks.
Um yeah, yeah. Um
Yeah, well, I mean, it's yeah, it's
interesting cuz Rwanda and
and
Congo were both Belgian colonies, so
it's not like like their colonial
experience differed that much. They were
both
raped by King Leopold. Um
I guess
I mean, but why does nobody care? Nobody
cares I think this is because it's very
remote, it's hard to get to, and if
you're a reporter who's interested in
Congo and like I want to be stationed
out there, I want to go out there for a
couple of months, you could never like
if I called everyone I know, I could
never get anyone in radio, TV, or the
internet, or print to send me to Congo.
It's a no [__] way. No one's
interested, no one will publish anything
about it. They American It's not the
BBC. American media outlets give no
shits about it, which is why the
American people It's completely off
their radar. Which is why I watch BBC.
6:00 every day on PBS if you don't have
access to the actual BBC. Uh Beats and
Meats, thanks for the 999. Do you think
Putin will threaten Israel with nukes if
they threaten Iran with nukes?
Uh this is essentially what Professor
Jiang hypothesized a few years ago in
his infamous video, The Iran Trap.
I don't think so. Yeah, I don't
Honestly, I think the I think the
Russians are far more responsible on
this issue than the Israelis are.
I don't think I don't think they'll make
any threats like that. Frank Ham, $5. I
have a family friend traveling to Europe
next week, is worried about terror
attacks because of the Iran war. Would I
tourist travel?
I guess I would now.
But I'd be more worried in a year than
I'd be worried next week. How about you,
John?
I agree with that. There There will
always be a threat from lone wolves.
Wolves.
And um
And it it's true that the Iranians have
cells here and there around the world. I
mean, if you're talking about traveling
in Europe, no, I don't think there's any
problem. I think I think Western
audiences always kind of think that, you
know, there's going to be a a quick
reaction to this sort of thing. That's
not That's just not how it is. But there
will be a reaction. Oh, yes. Thanks for
the $2 $2 tip on Rumble wallet. We are
number eight in the nation right now on
Rumble. I think we have like over 2,000
live people watching live on YouTube. So
thank you to all you guys. Um
Will the Kurdish people one day achieve
independence and full freedom? Muhammad
wants to know. I believe so.
I sure hope so.
You know, we've talked about this a
minute here and a minute there for a
long time. You and I both love the
Kurds. You and I both support Kurdish
independence. Absolutely. I don't see it
happening, you know, Not soon. Right.
Right. But I sure hope someday
the Kurds have their their independence.
They deserve it. They deserve it. It's
been promised to them. I mean
>> Many times. Yeah. By by the biggest
powers. And they need it.
I mean, they have they really do need
it.
Um
Let's see.
Okay.
Let's see. Someone's asking, please try
to answer Just Samantha, what did you
ask, Just Samantha? Channel activity.
Um, please answer my my super chat
question. I don't know. Um,
Robbie, try to find Samantha's question,
please. Uh, I'm sorry, things are
moving. Anyone in the scroll knows this
is really happening fast. Uh, Meow Meow
wants to know, is this happening because
Benjamin Netanyahu is up for election
this year?
Well, it's not not a reason.
>> It can't hurt.
Yeah, it's not not a reason. That's it.
That's it, Ted. Yes.
Yeah, that and the and the uh ongoing
felony corruption charges pending
against him. So long as he's the prime
minister, he's not going to prison.
Uh, why would the State Department list
Egypt as some somewhere Americans should
immediately depart from or I should say
depart to? Or depart from? Israel
wouldn't be dumb enough to strike it,
Trump's favorite dictator, right? No,
no, that's not it at all. That's not it.
>> It's that the Arab street really doesn't
like Americans.
And so, sure, while we're buddy-buddy
with the the military dictatorship
that rules [clears throat] Egypt,
the average Egyptian is pretty darn
angry at us right now. No doubt. No
doubt. Um, Tammy, thanks um thanks for
the question. We'd like to like to know
our opinion on uh Ayatollah Khamenei as
a leader and as a person. Thank you for
your reply. That's a good question. You
know, Ted, yesterday I did an interview,
I don't even remember I've done so many,
I can't remember with whom. I did one
last night.
And I stole one of your lines that
really went over well. Okay.
Killing uh
killing uh Khamenei
is like killing the Pope. You kill the
Pope, you don't bring down Catholicism.
They just pick another Pope.
Well, killing uh Khamenei is not going
to bring down Iran or Shiism. They're
just going to pick another Grand
Ayatollah.
And he may be worse.
Yeah,
that is 100% right.
Do we think Trump had the foresight to
seize control of Venezuela's oil before
destabilizing the Middle East?
>> Yes.
Yes, I believe that is indeed the case.
That's crazy. Just in case
we screw things up and the Straits of
Hormuz are closed, which they could be
closed in the next, you know, 8 hours.
Hello from Vietnam. Thank you for the
show. Sudden notice from the State
Department for Americans to get out of
the Middle East by any means necessary.
How should the average Americans try to
get out in such a situation? The
economic fallout's going to be massive.
Which dominoes do we see falling first
and how will it affect the rest of the
globe?
I have a lot of experience escaping
places that are going tits up. Um
I would say first of all, I like land
crossings.
Oh, land crossings are better as a rule,
but if you're not sure Oh, travel with
locals. That's also one of my big pieces
of advice. Like offer if you know some
locals who want to go somewhere, go with
them in their shitty local vehicle. Um
is always a way to go. Like when I was
leaving
>> That's how you get out of Afghanistan.
That's how I got out of Afghanistan,
yeah.
I was like all wrapped up in scarves in
the back of an old Soviet pickup truck.
Um
and you know,
and we offered like the locals like,
"Hey, you know, you want to go? Free
ride, come on, more the merrier."
Um but also, you might want to hunker
down.
I think you're more of a target when
you're in you're in motion.
Yeah. Um
>> That's a good point.
>> Which which economic dominoes will
follow will follow first?
I don't know. Trump's Trump's chances in
the midterm elections.
>> [sighs]
>> Yeah, you know, we should talk about
that actually. Mhm.
If only 1/3 of Republicans think this is
a good idea,
and if this thing
extends beyond, you know, the next three
or four weeks,
we're potentially looking at an
anti-Republican bloodbath
coming in in November. John, you know I
wrote my column this week and I I you've
you've kept your your counsel about what
you think of it about the possibility of
a canceled election.
But I'm not alone now in my paranoia.
The Atlantic and NPR both are
entertaining the same possibility.
Yes, that is true. Um more and more
people are talking about it. It's not a
bad idea.
I'll tell you it's never happened before
in American history. No. Never.
Uh but elections have been delayed. Yes,
the New York mayoral race
um
was delayed on 9/11. And it changed the
outcome. And it changed the outcome and
Mike Bloomberg won. Yeah, it would have
been Mark Green otherwise and everyone's
like, "Who?" It's like, "Exactly." No,
Mark Green was great. Oh, I know. He
would have been a fantastic mayor of New
York.
>> have been absolutely one of the best.
Totally. He was great. He was great. You
know, he was he he he was consumer
advocate for New York City. And among
the two things that he did is he said
women get overcharged for haircuts. Why
should women get charged more for
haircuts than men? So he passed a law to
make it the same. And he said, "Why
should a woman's blouse cost more to dry
clean than a man's shirt? It's the same
exact object."
>> Yes. So um but then all that was
reversed under Bloomberg. Um Kieran,
thanks for the 5 lbs. We see the BBC We
see the BBC is biased in the UK, but in
the US it's seen as a less biased. I
find that crazy how bad the propaganda
is in the US.
Um
my take on that, John, is that the BBC
is
less trustworthy about things in the UK.
Oh, yeah. But, you know, in other words,
if I were in England, I'd want to watch
non-English news about domestic British
stuff. Yes.
>> But, you know, but the BBC is less
biased about the US. It is. It is. The
BBC has
has a long history of
of offering both sides. Which we we
don't do here in the United States. And
you know what? When I was in the CIA and
we were getting ready to to to liberate
Kuwait, it would drive me crazy to watch
the BBC and and they say,
um,
yeah, the the Iraqis invaded Kuwait, but
the poor starving Iraqi children, the
sanctions are killing them. And it's
like, but
but food's not sanctioned. It's this
It's just that Saddam won't distribute
the food. That drove me nuts. Sodan,
thank Speaking of of Saddam, Sodan, uh,
with just a minute or two left, thanks
for the $49.99. Very generous.
>> you. Thank you, Sodan. Thank you.
>> and Gaddafi the buffer for us with Iran?
Yes.
They Yeah, they were the
counterbalances. The user, thanks for
the 219 Turkish Lira. What's the end
game for Israel? No country active
besides Turkey in terms of what's ahead
in the region. Europe is asleep and
other Gulf countries are just not as
effective.
I don't know. I mean,
Israel is
they're on the [__] warpath, man. And
I don't know
>> They are. It's like they're
>> for a bruising, too.
You know, we're the only ones who can
tell them stop, and we just won't do it.
No. That's what's needed. We need to
elect a a president who would just cut
them off once and for all. Um,
we are at now 9:59.
I am very apologetic. There was just no
way to get to all of your questions,
many of which were really great and
deserved to be answered today.
But, the good news is we're back
tomorrow and Thursday and Friday. And we
will have Achilles Larrea with us at
9:15 Eastern Time tomorrow. We're here
at 9:00 a.m. Eastern Monday through
Friday. We'll be back tomorrow at 9:00.
Thanks for tuning in. Please like,
follow, and share the show. Thank you
once again for your generous support of
Robbie Aid, allowing us to do this show
together. John, always great to see you.
Please stay tuned for the TMI show with
me and Manila Chan. That's coming up
right now.
>> [music]